Inventory of the Allan Hoover collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Allan Hoover collection
1927-1966
2015C7
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Photographs and ephemera relating to the Bohemian Club of San Francisco. Includes photographs of Herbert Hoover and other club members at Bohemian Grove encampments and other locations. In part collected by Fred G. Clark.
Hoover, Allan, collector.
Clark, Fred G. (Fred George), 1890-1973.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Photographs and ephemera relating to the Bohemian Club of San Francisco. Includes photographs of Herbert Hoover and other club members at Bohemian Grove encampments, picnic areas outside the Grove, and at George Mardikian's home in San Francisco.
The photographs were collected by Allan Hoover, son of Herbert Hoover, and Fred G. Clark. Captions on the back of some photos are in Herbert Hoover's hand, which suggests that the photos originally belonged to Herbert Hoover.
Bohemian Club (San Francisco, Calif.); Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964--Pictorial works.
- Photographs, 1927-1966
  Scope and Contents note
  Collection of photographs, mainly taken at the Bohemian Grove. Generally includes portraits of members, gatherings, social events, performances, facilities, and special events.
  - 1954-1958, undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Includes Herbert Hoover's 80th birthday.
  - 1952-1958, undated (Box-folder 1: 2)
    Includes an event in San Francisco with Herbert Hoover and Fred Clark in biplane.
  - 1954-1958, undated (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - 1953-1959, undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
    Includes Herbert Hoover and Nixon, and Herbert Hoover's 80th birthday.
  - 1949-1962 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    Contains images of Herbert Hoover's lakeside speeches.
  - 1953-1961 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - 1927-1966 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - 1927-1960, undated (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - 1958, undated (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - 1935-1961, undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - 1953-1961, undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - 1953-1959, undated (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - 1953-1958, undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Portraits of Herbert Hoover and group, 1940, undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
- "Bohemia Welcomes Herbert Hoover to the Old Guard," invitation, 1953 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Birthday well wishes presented to Herbert Hoover by the Bohemian Club, 1954 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  Original and copy.